In this clip we are going to discuss the use of black and white and color elements in our company logo.
For this task we will be using Adobe Illustrator for its useful layout capabilities.
Now Illustrator is a registered trademark of Adobe and I am in no way affiliated with Adobe.
A logo presented in vivid color will grab people's attention.
However, there are many occasions when the use of a multi-colored logo just will not be practical.
When the budget allows a full color logo will always be the most affective, but the smart use of a spot color can be just as eye catching.
A spot color is a secondary color that compliments the primary color on your logo.
One of the most important things you should consider is how you will use your finished logo.
A design that will most often be printed on a white background for instance will open up endless spot color options.
Conversely a logo that is destined to be displayed on a solid black background primarily will limit the spot color choices.
In this case you probably would not want to use a dark spot color like a blue or brown for instance since much of the logo's detail will blend into the background rendering the design ineffective.
Try different combinations of spot colors that will work no matter what the background.
There are some instances when the designer will be forced to use a black and white logo due to budget constraints.
Often times fliers, business cards, vehicle graphics, and broadcast graphics can present other challenges to the designer.
Once such challenge is to take their multi-colored logo design and reduce it to a single color that still retains its effectiveness.
This is where a strong logo icon and bold logo type will really stand out.
The smart designer will always consider the colors and the final use when beginning the design process.
This concludes are look at incorporating black and white and color in our logo design.